I learned something about mini Cube uh
as I was setting up a storage class I
set up a storage class at home I mean I
set up a c a cluster at home and then
realized I did not have a storage class
now I knew I knew that you needed to add
a storage class and you can watch the
big long video of me doing that but
there's actually a really interesting
tidbit that I learned about mini Cube um
mini Cube and I'm going to read it uh in
chat gpt's words um mini Cube can
dynamically PR provision persistent
volumes for persistent volume claims
using host path but it does so using an
internal default storage class called
standard it's very special it's very
customized and it's this thing that's
been added to mini Cube why is that
important because if you're like me
you're going to you see you know you're
all proud because you know you finally
got your kubernetes cluster on Prem with
Cube ADM running and you're like oh
great and then you go try out your thing
and all of a sudden there's no you can't
create any PVC persistent volume claims
so I had a PVC and the reason that this
didn't work is because any for those of
you who know know kubernetes for any PVC
you need a PV a physical persistent
volume but in almost every case every
cluster you ever normally work with
including mini cube when you create a
PVC the system kubernetes itself
whatever the provisioner whatever I
don't even know what thing it is it will
actually create a PV to go with the PVC
if there isn't one there and it will use
the system default storage class
whatever that is and in the case of hey
hi in in the case of this we're actually
seeing that the persistent volume claim
that's being created is is not was not
being created I was like what the hell
mini Cube did it and now I'm learning
that mini cube is special mini Cube uses
a host path provisioner which is a host
path is one of the default storage
classes you still have to add it by the
way host path is a storage class that
uses the local disc that's attached to
each node and you don't normally almost
never want to use that because that
means that storage can't be used
anywhere else right so like if if you
wanted to use you know and that's you
know we'll get into storage classes
later the the video is about one thing
mini Cube Breaks the Rules mini Cube
creates a persistent volume uh uh for a
persistent volume claim even though host
path storage class does not
dynamically it does not dynamically
create PVS for each PVC which means that
in in in my case my manifest I did not
have the creation of a PB because I
thought it would get automatically
created now there's two ways to fix that
one of them would be you know install a
storage class that does dynamic
provisioning which includes NFS by the
way which is what I'm going to do or use
mini Cube which has this built-in hack
to to make it work and and yeah I'm
going to avoid a rant right here because
I'm kind of annoyed by this because mini
cube is actually building a false
expectation that your PBS are going to
be created for you when they are not
going to be created for you unless you
do it so there you go take it or leave
it but maybe that'll explain why mini
Cube worked for your PBC without your PB
manifest and why an actual kubernetes
cluster doesn't work doing the same
thing